Hello everyone and welcome back to
English Pod. My name is Marco. My name is
Katherine and today we've got a very
nerve-wracking situation for you. That's
right we are going to meet the in-laws.
Meaning the in-laws. So for in-laws these
are the parents of your husband or wife.
Right so in this case you have the
mother-in-law and your father-in-law.
That's right so we're meeting these
people for the very first time. You can
imagine how nervous the man is who's
meeting his future wife's
parents. Let's learn all
about what they talk
about in today's dialogue.
Mother, father, I'd like to introduce
you to my fiance Bob. Hello Bob, welcome.
Thanks for having me nice to meet the both
of you. I've heard so much. So Cindy told
you about bringing a home or
last boyfriend then. That idiot.
First and you're going
to scare the poor boy.
Come in have a drink.
Dinner will be on in just a bit.
What'll you be having? Whisky,
bourbon, pick your poison.
If you have a lemonade
let that be great. Lemonade.
I'm sure there's
some in the fridge.
Mother makes her own lemonade from scratch.
It's the best. So what are your
hobbies son? If you want we can do some
hunting tomorrow. I've just picked up a
new rifle I've been meaning to try out.
Should be a real hoot. I'm not really
I don't really hunt. You don't hunt.
We'll all beat there. Bob is an animal
rights activist. He doesn't believe
in harming animals. Dinner's ready.
Let's go out to the patio where the pig
is roasting. Roast pig? I'm a vegetarian.
All right we're back. So a very awkward
situation. I think they might have a
little bit of a problems in the future.
Yeah there's there are a lot of
cultural differences between the the
characters the son-in-law and the new
parents the father-in-law. Yeah. So
it's really interesting why don't we start
off by looking at a couple of
different words on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So first of all we
have the two characters Cindy and Bob
who are getting married. So we call them
we call Bobs and these fiancé. Right so
my fiancé and it comes from French
and it means to the the person that you're
going to get married to. That's right
the person you've decided to get married
to. So we say fiancé we can say
the same word for a man or a woman.
So he is my fiancé. She is my fiancé. Okay
my fiancé very good. So Cindy introduces
her fiancé Bob to her parents and
they start talking a little bit and her dad
Thurston invites him to go do some hunting
tomorrow. That's right so hunting is a
sport in America and lots of places
in the world where you shoot animals.
Okay so you go in the woods you wear brown
and green colors and you shoot animals to
take them home and skin them and
eat them or to keep them in as trophies.
Alright so you go hunting and well the
way that you shoot these animals is you
need to have a rifle. A rifle so you
could also call it a hunting rifle in this
case. A rifle is a gun but it's a very
long gun. Right so it's not a little gun
that you just hold in your hand.
It's very long it'll be maybe like half a
meter long. That's right and so
oftentimes people when they're hunting they
lie on the ground and they wait
for the animals to pass and they hide
themselves and then they shoot from a
long distance. Right so he's talking about
hunting he's got a new rifle and he
says yeah we should definitely go it
should be a real hoot. Should be a real
hoot. This is a very fun spoken English
phrase. It's said more by older people
than by younger people so this is why the
father says it in the dialogue.
A hoot should be a real good time real fun.
So how can you can use this like oh
the party last night was a real hoot? Yep
you can say that. You can say or
she's a real hoot. She's really funny.
Okay but this is a little bit more like
a spoken and for use by maybe older
people right? My mother would say this.
I wouldn't say this so oh my goodness it
was a real hoot. Alright so he's talking
about hunting how much fun they would
have and fortunately Bob is an animal
rights activist. Oh what does it mean?
So an animal rights activist is someone
who is very concerned with protecting the
rights of animals. So for example if
I'm an animal rights activist maybe I will
protest people who wear fur or perhaps
I will also try and secure land for a
natural wildlife preserve so that
animals can live in the wild there's not
houses or cars. So animal rights activists
are people who try to make sure that
animals are protected from human beings.
Okay very good and this is what Bob
is so obviously Bob is not really into
hunting right? I'm guessing no these are
two opposites you have people who
like to kill animals and people who want to
protect the lives of animals. Right okay
well and to finish off our language take
away dinner is ready so let's go out
to the patio. Okay a patio is a space
outside the house usually in the back
that's paved so there's like cement or
bricks or some kind of tile and that's
where you have a table and chairs or
some place to sit and rest. This is
where you have a grill so it's an outdoor
area but it's not grass. Okay so it's
not your backyard or it could be in your
backyard. The patio could be in the
backyard. That's right but the ground in
the patio is not grass. It's some kind
of material like cement or brick or wood
okay very good so great words there
why don't we listen to the dialogue again
and we'll be back in a bit with
fluency builder. Fluency builder. All right
we're back so we have three great phrases
here on fluency builder why don't we
start off with the first one. So the
first one we have to go back to the very
beginning of this dialogue and think
about these people who are introducing
each other for the very first time.
Cindy says I want to introduce you to my
fiance Bob Bob says to Cindy's parents
I've heard so much. I've heard so much
okay so this phrase you can usually use
it when you meet somebody for the first
time. I've heard so much about you.
That's right so the longer version is I've
heard so much about you. Basically you're
saying listen Cindy talks about you a lot.
I've heard really nice things.
Sometimes people like to joke you say
I've heard so much about you. They say
hmm I hope only good things. No I hope
not too much. I hope not too much. So
this is a very polite way to respond when
someone introduces themselves. Okay I've
heard so much about you it's a pleasure to
finally meet you. Exactly. Okay so
they started talking and actually thirst in
the office and the drink he says well
what do you want? Whiskey, bourbon, pick
your poison. All right this is one of
my very favorite phrases in English.
The father-in-law wants to give the
new son-in-law drink and there are many
different options. So pick your poison
means pick your drink. You might hear
this at a bar. What do you want to drink?
Well pick your poison. You could have
whiskey, rum. So usually we're just
talking about alcohol like drinks. Okay so
you wouldn't really use this for
juices or water. This is for alcohol.
Okay so if you say pick your poison that's
for alcohol right or maybe you can ask
somebody what they're drinking you
would say what's your poison. Yeah what's
your poison. Okay so poison in this
case is a slang term for alcohol. Very good
and finally when Cindy was talking
about lemonade that her mother makes she
said she makes it from scratch to make
something from scratch. You could say my
mother makes chocolate chip cookies
from scratch. This means to not to buy
something in the store but to make
it all yourself from nothing. So making
lemonade from scratch means taking lemons,
cutting them, taking a juice, adding
some sugar so you're making it from
nothing. Okay you're not using some kind of
kit or some kind of you know canned drink
from the store. Okay so for example maybe
some Italians and Italy make their
spaghetti from scratch with flour and they
need it and they make everything from
scratch. Wow so you don't buy a box of
spaghetti but you actually have to
cut the spaghetti and pull it and exactly.
Very very hard work. So to make something
from scratch and usually you can add the
something goes in between right to make
lemonade from scratch. Make bread from
scratch. Make ice cream from scratch. Okay
so those are three phrases for today let's
listen to the dialogue for
one last time and we'll be
back to talk about this
very very interesting topic.
Mother, father, I'd like to introduce
you to my fiance Bob. Hello Bob, welcome.
Thanks for having me nice to meet
the both of you. I've heard so much.
So Cindy told you about bringing a
Homer last boyfriend then. That idiot.
First and you're going to scare the poor
boy. Come in and have a drink. Dinner will
be on in just a bit. What'll you be having?
Whiskey, bourbon, pick your poison. If you
have a lemonade that'd be great. Lemonade.
I'm sure there's some in the fridge.
Mother makes her own lemonade from scratch.
It's the best. So what are your
hobbies son? If you want we can do some
hunting tomorrow. I've just picked up a new
rifle I've been meaning to try out. Should
be a real hoot. I'm not really... I don't
really hunt. You don't hunt. We'll all beat
down. Bob is an animal rights activist.
He doesn't believe
in harming animals.
Dinner's ready. Let's go
out to the patio where
the pig is roasting. Roast pig,
I'm a vegetarian this is a very scary
topic for a lot of people. I think they
get very nervous introducing themselves
because in this case Bob is going to be
marrying Cindy. So these are going to be
his in-laws forever. Yeah and it seems
interesting. The difference is as you
mentioned before between the father-in-law
who's very much into hunting and
drinks and likes roast pig whereas this
guy is more of an animal rights activist
doesn't drink. He's a vegetarian. He's
a vegetarian. So I think it would be very
complicated and I think this happens
a lot also with people from different
cultures, right? Maybe you're Asian
and you're marrying an American or
something like this. Yeah that's right.
I think it can be very very difficult.
I recently went to a wedding between a
Chinese girl and an American guy and it
was amazing to see all these people
getting together because the families were
so different but they all got along
really well. It was really fun. They were
all very supportive. They were just
excited for their kids. Yeah but I think it
can be a little bit difficult, right?
I mean being in a family where the
culture is so different or the traditions
and the customs are are strange to
you. But it's exciting because then as a
you know family the young people who
are getting married they can pick the
traditions they want and make new traditions.
So this is very interesting topic
we want to know maybe if you are
married how did it go when you met
your in-laws are you very different or did
you get along very well or how is it
in your country? Yeah please do let us
know our website is www.engushpod.com. We
hope to see you there. Alrighty one. Bye.